<root>
  <job>
    <name>Computer Network Support Specialists </name>
    <summary>Computer Network Support Specialists - Analyze, test, troubleshoot, and evaluate existing network systems, such as local area network (LAN), wide area network (WAN), and Internet systems or a segment of a network system. Perform network maintenance to ensure networks operate correctly with minimal interruption.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>18</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>6</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafayette Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Plaquemines Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Terrebonne Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Calcasieu Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Iberia Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Iberville Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Jefferson Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>Percent change in employment, projected 2012-22 Computer user support specialists 20% Computer support specialists 17% Total, all occupations 11% Computer network support specialists 7% Note: All Occupations includes all occupations in the U.S. Economy. Source: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Employment Projections program Employment of computer support specialists is projected to grow 17 percent from 2012 to 2022, faster than the average for all occupations. More support services will be needed as organizations upgrade their computer equipment and software. Computer support staff will be needed to respond to the installation and repair requirements of increasingly complex computer equipment and software. However, a rise in cloud computing could increase the productivity of computer support specialists, slowing their growth at many firms. Growth will be highest at firms that provide cloud-computing technology. Employment of support specialists in computer systems design and related firms is projected to grow 49 percent from 2012 to 2022. Employment growth also should be strong in healthcare industries. This field is expected to greatly increase its use of information technology (IT), and support services will be crucial to keep everything running properly. Some lower level tech support jobs, commonly found in call centers, may be sent to countries that have lower wage rates. However, a recent trend to move jobs to lower cost regions of the United States may offset some loss of jobs to other countries. Job Prospects Job prospects should be favorable. There are usually clear advancement possibilities for computer support specialists, creating new job openings. Applicants with a bachelor’s degree and a strong technical background should have the best job opportunities.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Computer Network Support Specialists in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>There is no data available for Louisiana.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Computer Systems Engineers/Architects </name>
    <summary>Computer Systems Engineers/Architects - Design and develop solutions to complex applications problems, system administration issues, or network concerns. Perform systems management and integration functions.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>45</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>18</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>8</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Rapides Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>4</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Tammany Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>3</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Caddo Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Ouachita Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Jefferson Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafayette Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Plaquemines Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Calcasieu Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>There is no data available for Computer Systems Engineers/Architects in Louisiana.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Computer Systems Engineers/Architects in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Database Architects </name>
    <summary>Database Architects - Design strategies for enterprise database systems and set standards for operations, programming, and security. Design and construct large relational databases. Integrate new systems with existing warehouse structure and refine system performance and functionality.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>4</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Bossier Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>There is no data available for Database Architects in Louisiana.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Database Architects in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>There is no data available for Louisiana.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Information Security Analysts </name>
    <summary>Information Security Analysts - Plan, implement, upgrade, or monitor security measures for the protection of computer networks and information. May ensure appropriate security controls are in place that will safeguard digital files and vital electronic infrastructure. May respond to computer security breaches and viruses.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>33</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Vernon Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>19</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>7</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Bossier Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>Percent change in employment, projected 2012-22 Information security analysts 37% Computer occupations 18% Total, all occupations 11% Note: All Occupations includes all occupations in the U.S. Economy. Source: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Employment Projections program Employment of information security analysts is projected to grow 37 percent from 2012 to 2022, much faster than the average for all occupations. Demand for information security analysts is expected to be very high. Cyberattacks have grown in frequency and sophistication over the last few years, and many organizations are behind in their ability to detect these attacks. Analysts will be needed to come up with innovative solutions to prevent hackers from stealing critical information or creating havoc on computer networks. The federal government is expected to greatly increase its use of information security analysts to protect the nation’s critical information technology (IT) systems. In addition, as the healthcare industry expands its use of electronic medical records, ensuring patients’ privacy and protecting personal data are becoming more important. More information security analysts are likely to be needed to create the safeguards that will satisfy patients’ concerns. Job Prospects Job prospects for information security analysts should be good. Information security analysts with related work experience will have the best opportunities. For example, an applicant with experience as a database administrator would have better prospects in database security than someone without that experience.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Information Security Analysts in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Information Technology Project Managers </name>
    <summary>Information Technology Project Managers - Plan, initiate, and manage information technology (IT) projects. Lead and guide the work of technical staff. Serve as liaison between business and technical aspects of projects. Plan project stages and assess business implications for each stage. Monitor progress to assure deadlines, standards, and cost targets are met.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>41</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Ouachita Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>10</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>8</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>8</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafayette Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>6</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Rapides Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Jefferson Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Caddo Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Calcasieu Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Tammany Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>There is no data available for Information Technology Project Managers in Louisiana.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Information Technology Project Managers in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Network and Computer Systems Administrators </name>
    <summary>Network and Computer Systems Administrators - Install, configure, and support an organization's local area network (LAN), wide area network (WAN), and Internet systems or a segment of a network system. Monitor network to ensure network availability to all system users and may perform necessary maintenance to support network availability. May monitor and test Web site performance to ensure Web sites operate correctly and without interruption. May assist in network modeling, analysis, planning, and coordination between network and data communications hardware and software. May supervise computer user support specialists and computer network support specialists. May administer network security measures.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>66</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Bossier Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>17</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>16</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>14</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafayette Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Ouachita Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Tammany Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Jefferson Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Terrebonne Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafourche Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Tangipahoa Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>Percent change in employment, projected 2012-22 Computer occupations 18% Network and computer systems administrators 12% Total, all occupations 11% Note: All Occupations includes all occupations in the U.S. Economy. Source: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Employment Projections program Employment of network and computer systems administrators is projected to grow 12 percent from 2012 to 2022, about as fast as the average for all occupations. Demand for information technology workers is high and should continue to grow as firms invest in newer, faster technology and mobile networks. However, an increase in cloud computing could raise the productivity of network administrators, slowing their growth across many industries. Growth will be highest at industries that provide cloud-computing technology. Employment of network administrators in the computer systems design and related services industry is projected to grow 35 percent from 2012 to 2022. Growth is also expected in healthcare industries as their use of information technology increases. More administrators will be required to manage the growing systems and networks found at hospitals and other healthcare institutions. Job Prospects Job opportunities should be favorable for this occupation. Prospects should be best for applicants who have a bachelor’s degree in computer science and who are up to date on the latest technology, especially cloud computing.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Network and Computer Systems Administrators in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Software Developers, Applications </name>
    <summary>Software Developers, Applications - Develop, create, and modify general computer applications software or specialized utility programs. Analyze user needs and develop software solutions. Design software or customize software for client use with the aim of optimizing operational efficiency. May analyze and design databases within an application area, working individually or coordinating database development as part of a team. May supervise computer programmers.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>85</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>30</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>23</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Jefferson Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>7</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafayette Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>7</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Tammany Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>6</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Ouachita Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lincoln Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>3</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Caddo Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Rapides Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Natchitoches Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>Percent change in employment, projected 2012-22 Software developers, applications 23% Software developers 22% Software developers, systems software 20% Total, all occupations 11% Note: All Occupations includes all occupations in the U.S. Economy. Source: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Employment Projections program Employment of software developers is projected to grow 22 percent from 2012 to 2022, much faster than the average for all occupations. Employment of applications developers is projected to grow 23 percent, and employment of systems developers is projected to grow 20 percent. The main reason for the rapid growth is a large increase in the demand for computer software. Mobile technology requires new applications. The healthcare industry is greatly increasing its use of computer systems and applications. Also, concerns over threats to computer security could result in more investment in security software to protect computer networks and electronic infrastructure. Systems developers are likely to see new opportunities because of an increase in the number of products that use software. For example, computer systems are built into consumer electronics, such as cell phones, and into other products that are becoming computerized, such as appliances. In addition, an increase in software offered over the Internet should lower costs and allow more customization for businesses, also increasing demand for software developers. Some outsourcing to foreign countries with lower wages may occur. However, because software developers should be close to their customers, the offshoring of this occupation is expected to be limited. Job Prospects Job prospects will be best for applicants with knowledge of the most up-to-date programming tools and languages.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Software Developers, Applications in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Software Quality Assurance Engineers and Testers </name>
    <summary>Software Quality Assurance Engineers and Testers - Develop and execute software test plans in order to identify software problems and their causes.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>37</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>7</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Caddo Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>6</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Calcasieu Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>4</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Charles Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>4</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>West Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>3</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Martin Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Tammany Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Rapides Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Bernard Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>There is no data available for Software Quality Assurance Engineers and Testers in Louisiana.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Software Quality Assurance Engineers and Testers in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Telecommunications Engineering Specialists </name>
    <summary>Telecommunications Engineering Specialists - Design or configure voice, video, and data communications systems. Supervise installation and post-installation service and maintenance.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>5</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>Avoyelles Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>3</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Rapides Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Terrebonne Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>Percent change in employment, projected 2012-22 Computer occupations 18% Computer network architects 15% Total, all occupations 11% Note: All Occupations includes all occupations in the U.S. Economy. Source: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Employment Projections program Employment of computer network architects is projected to grow 15 percent from 2012 to 2022, faster than the average for all occupations. Demand for computer network architects will increase as firms continue to expand their use of wireless and mobile networks. Designing and building these new networks, as well as upgrading existing ones will create opportunities for computer network architects. The expansion of healthcare information technology will also contribute to employment growth. Adoption of cloud computing, which allows users to access storage, software, and other computer services over the Internet, is likely to cause a decrease in the demand for computer network architects. Organizations will no longer have to design and build networks in-house; instead, firms that provide cloud services will do this. However, because architects at cloud providers can work on more than one organization’s network, these providers will not have to employ as many architects as individual organizations do for the same amount of work. Job Prospects Prospects for computer network architects should be favorable, as many companies report difficulty finding network architects because of the considerable amount of education and work experience required for these highly skilled positions.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Telecommunications Engineering Specialists in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need one or two years of training involving both on-the-job experience and informal training with experienced workers. A recognized apprenticeship program may be associated with these occupations.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Video Game Designers </name>
    <summary>Video Game Designers - Design core features of video games. Specify innovative game and role-play mechanics, story lines, and character biographies. Create and maintain design documentation. Guide and collaborate with production staff to produce games as designed.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>No Job Openings Data Available.</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>No Jobs area Distribution Data Available.</placename>
        <placenum>No Jobs area Distribution Data Available.</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>There is no data available for Video Game Designers in Louisiana.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Video Game Designers in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need several years of work-related experience, on-the-job training, and/or vocational training.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Web Administrators </name>
    <summary>Web Administrators - Manage web environment design, deployment, development and maintenance activities. Perform testing and quality assurance of web sites and web applications.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>No Job Openings Data Available.</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>No Jobs area Distribution Data Available.</placename>
        <placenum>No Jobs area Distribution Data Available.</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>There is no data available for Web Administrators in Louisiana.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Web Administrators in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need one or two years of training involving both on-the-job experience and informal training with experienced workers. A recognized apprenticeship program may be associated with these occupations.</work_exp>
  </job>
  <job>
    <name>Web Developers </name>
    <summary>Web Developers - Design, create, and modify Web sites. Analyze user needs to implement Web site content, graphics, performance, and capacity. May integrate Web sites with other computer applications. May convert written, graphic, audio, and video components to compatible Web formats by using software designed to facilitate the creation of Web and multimedia content.</summary>
    <jobs_avail>13</jobs_avail>
    <job_area_dist>
      <place>
        <placename>East Baton Rouge Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>5</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Jefferson Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>3</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Lafayette Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>Ouachita Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>2</placenum>
      </place>
      <place>
        <placename>St. Martin Parish, Louisiana</placename>
        <placenum>1</placenum>
      </place>
    </job_area_dist>
    <ntnl_supply_demand>Percent change in employment, projected 2012-22 Web developers 20% Computer and mathematical occupations 18% Total, all occupations 11% Note: All Occupations includes all occupations in the U.S. Economy. Source: U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, Employment Projections program Employment of web developers is projected to grow 20 percent from 2012 to 2022, faster than the average for all occupations. Employment of web developers is projected to grow as ecommerce continues to expand. Online purchasing is expected to grow faster than the overall retail industry. As retail firms expand their online offerings, demand for web developers will increase. Additionally, an increase in the use of mobile devices to search the web will also lead to an increase in employment of web developers. Instead of designing a website for a desktop computer, developers will have to create sites that work on mobile devices with many different screen sizes, leading to more work. Because websites can be built from anywhere in the world, some web developer jobs may be moved to countries with lower wages, decreasing employment growth. However, this practice may decline because of a growing trend of firms hiring workers in low-cost areas of the United States instead of in foreign countries. Job Prospects Job opportunities for web developers are expected to be good. Those with knowledge of multiple programming languages and digital multimedia tools, such as Flash and Photoshop, will have the best opportunities.</ntnl_supply_demand>
    <edu_req>There is no data available for Web Developers in Louisiana.</edu_req>
    <work_exp>Employees in these occupations usually need one or two years of training involving both on-the-job experience and informal training with experienced workers. A recognized apprenticeship program may be associated with these occupations.</work_exp>
  </job>
</root>